If you find yourself in need of legal
representation, it can be a very
stressful time in your life. In my
career, I have dealt with thousands of
lawyers. I've dealt with thousands of
law firms. And I can confidently
recommend to you Keith M. Davidson at
kmdaw.com. Available 24 hours, 7 days a
week. Just log into
kmdlaw.com. That's
kmdaw.com. Or you can call toll-free
8334kmdaw. That's 8334 KMD law. Personal
injury, wrongful death, STDs, sexual
assault, car accidents. They handle it
all efficiently and professionally. It
doesn't matter how imposing the
opposition may be because the team at
kmdlaw.com are battle tested and fierce.
They will not stop until just prevails.
Go to kmdlaw.com or call toll-free
8334kmdaw. If you're in for the fight of
your life, stop screwing around and
contact KMD Law. Before Epstein was the
Franklin coverup, before that the
Finders, and long before that, the
Cleveland Street scandal. Pedogate
Primer is a concise intro and overview
of a growing child abuse epidemic
worldwide. It features shocking
instances of institutionalized and
organizational pedophilia throughout
history. Churches, cults, the world of
arts and entertainment, the government,
NOS, charities, and major corporations
are all complicit or culprits in many
instances. Pedogate Primer delves into
material that for many may seem like the
stuff of conspiracy theories. For this
reason, the book draws on academic
resources, declassified documents, and
other reliable sources, and steers clear
of conjecture. Such shocking true
stories need no embellishment. A flooded
home or business is never easy to deal
with. You're left with a mess to clean
up, having to deal with the insurance
company to pay for the damages, not to
mention the memories that are lost that
you cannot replace. An aquedam can be
another tool in your arsenal to protect
your home or business from the
floodwaters, a hurricane, storm surge,
or the king tides. Give AquadamAM a call
at
707764-2119 or look us up online at
aquadam.net. We can help. We're also
offering 10% off the price to anyone who
mentions they heard this ad on the
Operman Report. Email revealer.com.
People ask me all the time, "Hey Ed, are
you still a private investigator?" I
sure am. Go to emailrevealer.com. We
handle adoption investigations,
infidelity investigations, where you
give us your spouse's email address, we
trace it back to online dating websites,
catch him cheating online, email
tracing, locate or identify somebody
from as little as an anonymous email
address, summon all your money, back
child support. We can find that
deadbeat, locate his hidden assets,
locate his hidden bank accounts, find
his current place of employment, and
even assist you in obtaining a judgment
and recover that judgment for you.
emailrevealer.com. Digital forensics,
computer forensics, cell phone
forensics, recover deleted text
messages. Create a report that you can
use in court. email revealer.com
800572-9762. It's the Operman Report.
Join digital forensic investigator and
PI Ed Operan for an in-depth discussion
of conspiracy theories, strategy of new
world order resistance, high-profile
court cases in the news, and interviews
with expert guests and authors on these
topics, and more. It's the Operan
Report. And now, here is
investigator Oper.
Okay, welcome to the Opperman Report.
I'm your host, private investigator Ed
Operman. You can find me at Operan
Investigations and Digital Forensic
Consulting, uh either through my
website, emailrevealer.com. You could
just email me directly at operin
investigations@gmail.com. If you like
our show, be sure and check out our
Patreon, OperanReport, Patreon. I got up
there pretty exclusively. They're
circulating now, but we had some
pictures of Stephen Avery uh that were
exclusive when I first put them up in
the free section on Patreon. So, be sure
and check that out. I was also
interviewed last night by Chuck Ochelli
and that's going to be going up in the
uh Patreon too as well. Uh, of course
our archives are free and you can find
them at spreaker.com and as a matter of
fact if you go to Sper you could find
our guest today John Kiri Kuryaku uh who
was a former CIA agent was actually
thrown in prison for whistleblowing
about all that torture that went on uh
over there in the Middle East. Uh so you
can find our first interview we did with
him which was a two-hour interview
covered a lot of material. Uh, but today
we're going to be talking about a CIA
hitman named Rick Praau. Okay. Who John
worked with and some other matters here.
John, are you there? I sure am. Thanks
for having me. Thank you so much. Now,
did I butcher your name? No. Kiryaku.
Perfect. Ah, I love you. Okay, great.
Uh, remind the audience who is John
Kuryaku. Well, I was a I was a CIA
officer for 15 years. Uh, the first half
of my career was in analysis on the
Middle East. The second half was in
counterterrorism operations. Uh after
that I went into the private sector a
little bit then went to the uh Senate
Foreign Relations Committee as the uh
senior investigator. I blew the whistle
on the CIA's torture program in uh 2007.
The CIA didn't appreciate that very much
and uh so they filed uh many many
charges against me. I ended up uh taking
a plea deal, which is a story in and of
itself, and did 23 months in prison.
Proud of what I did. No regrets. Would
do it again. And uh since I got out of
prison, which was about seven years ago,
a little bit more than seven years ago,
I've been um writing, doing lots of
radio. I've uh I've written seven books
and um just trying to trying to stay
relevant.
Seven years. I can't believe it. I
haven't had you John for seven years.
Um, yeah. Right. And time flies, man.
Uh, now one of the I guess the u side
effects of getting busted, arrested, and
convicted uh over these CIA charges was
is you lost your CIA pension. Yes. Yeah.
Right. And people don't even think of
that. Yeah. That's that's been the
hardest hit for me was losing the
pension. I mean, as things stand right
now, I'm going to have to work until the
day I die, which I probably would have
done anyway, but it would have been nice
to have been able to rely on that
pension. Yeah. Hopefully something can
come, you know, get some kind of a
pardon or something, you know, get
beyond that. I sure hope so. I thought I
was really close with Donald Trump. I
had a I had a champion in Tucker
Carlson and uh Tucker went to the mat
for me a couple of times. I was on his
show all the time and uh in the end uh
it it just didn't happen. I I had a nice
letter of support from from uh 70 former
CIA officers, from the guy who wrote the
law that I was convicted of violating. I
had a floor statement from my
congressman. I had a floor statement
from Senator John McCain. Alan Dersowitz
wrote a letter for me and um it it
wasn't good enough.
That's that's a shame. Hopefully
something will come up. Uh, you know,
you're still a young guy, you know. Uh,
but now there was something in the paper
though about Rudy Giuliani offering you
a pardon in exchange for some cash,
right? Yeah. Yeah. You know what I was
doing was I I hired a Republican
lobbyist to help me negotiate the Trump
White House. The Trump White House was
unlike any other White House I've ever
experienced in Washington. and I've been
in Washington for 40 years. Uh it it was
just I mean they were just breaking the
rules and making new policy every single
day. So this Republican lobbyist said,
"Look, we need to get in front of Rudy
Giuliani. Rudy Giuliani can get you a
pardon." And I said, "Well, I don't I
don't know Giuliani, but I know some
people close to him." So, um, I put out
a couple of calls and, uh, was referred
to a a friend and confidant of Giuliani
who sort of works as his chief of staff.
And, um, I called him and I said, you
know, this is John Kuryaku. He knew who
I was. And he said, let me guess, you're
calling about a pardon. And I said, yes,
I am, and I'd like to talk to uh, Mayor
Giuliani about it. And he said, well, as
it so happens, we're going to be in
Washington next week. Why don't we meet
up at the Trump Hotel? I said, "Great."
So, we we got together at the Trump
Hotel. You know, the funny thing is
before the meeting, uh the guy called me
back and said, "We should meet for lunch
because Rudy really enjoys
scotch." And by
2:00, he's enjoyed scotch a little too
much and he's unable to get any business
transacted. So, um I said that was fine.
it actually worked better for me. So, we
got together for lunch and um I'm
sitting there with the two of them and
two friends of mine who actually had
some some other business with Giuliani.
And uh finally during a lull in the
conversation, I said, "So, about this
pardon?" And as soon as I said it,
Giuliani said, "I got to hit the head."
And he gets up and he walks away. And I
said to his friend, "What just
happened?" And he said, "You never
discuss business with Rudy. You discuss
it with me and I discuss it with Rudy."
And I said,
"Okay." And the guy says, "Rudy's going
to want $2 million to do this." And I
laughed and I said, "First of all, I
don't have $2 million. I'll likely never
have $2 million. Secondly, even if I
did, why would I spend $2 million to
recoup a $700,000 pension? That's
ridiculous. And then Giuliani came back
from the men's room and we didn't
discuss it again. And that was the end
of it. And to tell you the truth, I just
forgot about it
until just before the end of the of the
Trump administration. like just days
before I was invited to a book party at
the Republican um the Republican club up
on Capitol Hill and I mentioned it to a
friend of mine as you know, hey, get a
load of this crazy story and my friend,
unbeknownst to me, um reported it to the
FBI. Wow. Yeah. And then the FBI called
me and I said I said I I don't have any
complaint. I said it wasn't a bribe. He
wanted me to hire him as a quote unquote
consultant because that's how Washington
works. You know, you cash in on on the
importance of your name. So, the FBI
never followed up on it. I wouldn't have
expected them to. And then I get a call
from the New York Times and they wanted
to hear the whole story. So, I ended up,
you know, it's funny. On the very very
final day of the Trump administration, I
got a call from Tucker Carlson, who had
been very, very kind to me and had
actively helped me to try to get a
pardon. And Tucker said, "Listen, I have
bad news from the White House." I said,
"Oh no, what's happening?" And he says,
"He's going to pardon effing Wayne. Can
you believe this? Little Wayne." And I
said, "I'm not exactly sure who that is,
but if somebody named Little Wayne can
get a pardon, and certainly I can get a
pardon." And he said, "Well, you can
come back on the show tonight." So, I
went back on the show the last day of
the Trump administration, and I
practically begged Donald Trump to
pardon me, and nothing happened.
I I tell you, the way you describe that,
I have pictures of Michael Corleó saying
he has to get up and go to the bathroom.
Yeah.
so melodramatic. It was just ridiculous.
Now, the thing Okay, now I'm kind of
familiar with this story. Was this the
book launch party? Burkenfeld's uh uh
the book about the Yes. Okay. It sure
was. Okay. Did you know that? Because I
had Burkenfeld on the
show. Okay. And plus, I've I've known
Betel for years. We don't we're not in
contact now, but we used to be very
close friends back in the 80s in New
York City. He's a dear dear close
friend. I I I love him. But uh but now
Okay. So, because now at the Bergenfeld
party also too, the figure of $2 million
was being bounded about uh involving the
sale of Hunter Biden's laptop.
Oh, how interesting. I didn't realize
they were asking for $2 million. Yeah.
What I got the word I got was that uh um
Abau's brother uh wanted to monetize the
laptop at that same party for $2
million. So, but that's but that was
like it was never offered to you like,
"Hey, John, you go in and get this
laptop for us."
I see. Maybe that I could have pulled
off. That's a catch. I I couldn't do it.
You tunnel in there, right? It's your
old CIA. Okay, man. Great. Okay, so
nothing came out of that. Now, the
friend who tipped off the FBI, is he
still your friend?
You know, it's funny. Um, he called me
and he said, "Please don't hang up on
me." And I said, "No, I'm I'm not going
to hang up on you. It's not my nature."
He says, "I'm calling to ask for your
forgiveness." And I said I said, "Yeah,
I forgive you, but why would you do
something like that? I have enough
problems in my life. Yeah, I don't need
to be on the front page of the New York
Times, you know, it's just too much."
And he said that he was so outraged at
what Giuliani had done. He just couldn't
keep it to himself. And so he called the
FBI and then he called the uh the New
York Times. And he called the New York
Times only because the FBI wouldn't
prosecute Giuliani. I said, "Buddy, you
got to back off. You got to back off.
Let me do this the way I need to do it.
Yeah. If you want to get something off
your chest, tell your bartender. Don't
call the FBI. Okay. You know what I'm
saying? The time of the day. My god,
what a story. Okay. What a fascinating
story. Now, the other thing I've always
wanted to get in touch with you and
clear up, okay, so you can set the
record straight is um there's this clip
going around or before it's news article
saying that John uh Kiryaku uh uh I
pronounced that correctly. Right,
Kuryaku? Sure did. Okay. Okay. John
Kiryaku um says that the CIA is involved
in sex trafficking of children, right?
Okay. That that's a quote attributed to
you. Yeah. What's the story? Absolutely
untrue. Okay. Absolutely untrue. First
of all, not only is the CIA not uh
involved in the sex trafficking of
children, but I most certainly never
said any such thing. What that came from
was I was giving a speech at American
University about ethics and I said that
at the
CIA there are no ethics classes. You
have to go into the CIA confident in
your own moral compass because there's
not going to be anybody to tell you
what's right and what's wrong, what's
legal and what's illegal. So, you have
to
be confident in yourself. And I said,
for example, I'm going to use a
hypothetical situation, and I do this
all the time in my speeches, especially
at colleges and universities, because I
want the audience to really think about
it. I said, "Let's say that you are a
CIA case officer and you've recruited a
penetration of a foreign intelligence
service. Let's say it's al-Qaeda, ISIS,
Hezbala, it doesn't matter, but they're
the real deal and they're really
dangerous." So, you've recruited a guy
who's a bonafide terrorist and he's
working for you for a year, two years,
and he's giving you actionable
intelligence that allows you to disrupt
attacks and to save American lives. So,
you meet with him once a month in a
hotel room somewhere in the Middle East,
Aman, Cairo, Damascus, wherever.
And then one day you go to do the
meeting and he says to you, "Listen,
I've given you everything you've ever
asked for and everything I've told you
is true. Now you're going to do
something for me. You're going to go get
me a prostitute." I said, "How many here
in the room would get him the
prostitute?" And usually about half the
hands go up. And I said, "The correct
answer is yes. at the CIA, you would get
him the the prostitute. This is a, you
know, despicable thing to do, but you
deal with scumbags. It's your job to
cultivate relations with dirty,
dangerous people. So, if he asks you for
the prostitute, sure, go get him the
prostitute. But what happens if he asks
you for a child prostitute? How many
would do that? And usually nobody raises
their hand. Once in a while you'll get
one or two people who very tentatively
will put their hand up. And I said the
answer is absolutely not. Not under any
circumstances should you go out and seek
a child prostitute to give to this
man. But the problem is that there's no
rule at the CIA saying you can't do
this. You have to know in your heart
that it's the wrong thing to do. I said,
that's why you have to go in with your
own level of
ethics. That's what I said. It's the
same speech that I give at every
university I go to. And then the next
thing I see is all over the internet and
I'm getting emails, like dozens of
emails thanking me for exposing child
sex trafficking at the CIA, these cabals
of child sex people in Washington. It's
like what what the heck happened? I
didn't even know where it came
from. But I never did any such thing.
This was just the basic standard speech
that I've had cleared by the CIA's
publications review board, by the way.
Same speech that I give all the time.
You know, it's a shame because these
people that they're so well-meaning, you
know, their hearts are in the right
place. You know what I mean? You're
you're absolutely right. and they're
just being taken advantage by husters
and you know um but no what about though
like when you were working in the Middle
East the stuff with that you hear about
this the dancing boys in Afghanistan a
lot of that was condoned by these at
least by these contractors right
absolutely
yeah that absolutely happened and it was
utterly disgraceful criminal was there
any policies or procedures in place
where you could report someone for that
or
Yes.
Um, that's kind of a hard question to
answer. The the Excuse me. The easy
answer.
Sorry. Oh, they they got him. They got
to John.
The poison pill. The easy answer is yes.
You can report it uh back to your
leadership. You can report it to the
inspector general's office. And to the
best of my
recollection, those reports were about
contractors and um military officials
that were sort of allowing that to
happen. And you know, I remember people
defending that at the time and saying,
"Well, this is a part of Afghan
culture." Yeah, it is. It's a part of
Afghan culture. It's a part of Yemen
culture to marry eight-year-olds. Wow.
Um but that's not cool either. So, we
shouldn't have any role in this at all.
It's just wrong. Yeah. I was supposed to
have an attorney come on on the show
once and talk about a lawsuit and along
those lines and uh one of the things was
you hear these stories about how people
working on the base uh would turn
against our soldiers and start shooting
up the place and and then you'd find out
that it was because the kid was one of
those dancing boys when he was a kid,
you know, and he was he was still
scarred by this his whole life. So,
yeah, I believe that. Yeah, I believe
that. What do you make of this? What's
going on in Ukraine real quick?
Well, you know, I I work for a Russian
uh radio network, Sputnik News. With
that said, they've never ever asked me
to say anything or to not say anything.
I've never been asked to change an
opinion or to squaltch my own opinion.
So, I want to start my answer to your
question by saying that I oppose the
Russian invasion of Ukraine
unreservedly. The Russians were wrong to
cross that border. This is a violation
of international law. Um it's a
violation of the human rights of all
Ukrainians and they should get out
immediately. Uh with that said, the
issue is is complicated. You know, the
the Russians the Russians were
legitimately frightened about NATO
expanding right up to its borders.
Already the Baltic states are NATO
members. Uh Lithuania, Latvia, and
Estonia. And you in the 1990s, the early
1990s, Bill
Clinton personally promised, he
guaranteed that NATO would not expand
eastward. And it it expanded eastward
unchecked. You know, Poland joined. Uh
like I said, the Baltic states, Romania,
Bulgaria, and the next thing you know,
here's Ukraine. Well, the Russians were
tired of being lied to and uh and they
put their foot down. Like I say, I'd
like to see them get the heck out of
Ukraine immediately. I think that uh
that Vladimir Putin um has committed
grave crimes by ordering and leading
this invasion. And uh I'm I'm hoping for
the best that it it ends quickly.
and we were talking off the air and even
despite this this pretty fair-handed uh
description here, the position you're
taking here, um you you were just
recently deplatformed over everything.
Yes. Yeah, we were
deplatformed everywhere. You know, it's
funny. This has been sort of a long time
in coming. I do a a segment on my show
every Thursday called Criminal
Injustice. Uh, I've got uh the
journalist Kevin Gustala and um a guy
named Paul Wright, the director of the
Human Rights Defense Center and the
publisher and editor of Prison Legal
News magazine. And every Thursday for 30
minutes, we talk about uh criminal
justice issues, you know, prison
conditions and solitary confinement and
animal grade food that's fed to
prisoners and and you know, medical
care, stuff like that. The Washington
Post ran an article about that segment
and it said that by broadcasting that
segment, I was weakening our
democracy. If you can imagine such a
thing, I was weakening our democracy by
talking about the US prison system. And
then the um uh uh CSIS, the Center for
Strategic and International Studies at
Georgetown University did a uh a paper,
an academic paper in which they said
that that my broadcasting that segment
uh showed the propaganda lengths that
Vladimir Putin will go to to try to
weaken um our democratic system. Well,
nobody's none of them denied that
anything I said was true. You know, I
have firsthand experience with the
American prison system. We should be
ashamed of our prison system compared to
our European allies at least. And so, I
thought it was just so rich that they
would declare that any criticism of the
United States is automatically Russian
propaganda. Like I talk to Vladimir
Putin every day and plan out the show
and how we're going to get the best
propaganda benefit from the show. It's
ridiculous. But in any event, once the
Russians crossed the uh Ukrainian
frontier, we were just deplatformed
everywhere. We were thrown off of
YouTube yesterday and then three weeks
ago we were thrown off of Spreaker,
Spotify, iTunes, iHeart Radio. Last week
we were thrown off of uh TuneIn and so
the only place where we appear now is is
Rumble. It's it's crazy that that
Rumble, which was set up as, you know,
the right-wing uh alternative to
YouTube, is the only place where people
can really exercise their freedom of
speech.
Yeah. The real threat to democracy is
this privatized censorship of the
private sector. Amen. you know, and
because just having you on the show now,
it puts fear into my heart that that I
don't want to get de demonetized and
deplatformed, you know, so it has an a
chilling effect on on freedom of speech
and freedom of the press. It's just
outrageous. And I think that's exactly
what they want. I think
Yeah. You think
so? Yeah. Yeah. They're putting a lot of
effort in. Now, recently, too, I had
Barrett Brown on the show recently, and
I've had terrific reality winner's
mother. I had her on the show. I tried
to get Reality Winner to come on the
show and she tells me and I can't uh
because they're they're all over me and
I got to watch my back here. Yeah. You
know, the the sad story about Reality
Winner is they've gone after her for
whatever reason. They've gone after her
even more than they've gone after any of
the other national security
whistleblowers to the point where um
they won't allow her to do interviews.
Yeah. and she and I have talked about
this and I I said I I really believe
that this is challengeable in court like
you know for example um when I first got
out of prison I was offered a job at a
think tank in Washington the Institute
for Policy Studies. They offered me a
job that would allow me to write about
uh prison reform issues. And the Bureau
of Prisons said that it would be
inappropriate for inmate Kuryaku to
write about prison reform issues. And I
said inmate Kuryaku, and I wasn't an
inmate at the time. Uh I was home. I
said, "Inmate Kiryaku never gave up his
First Amendment rights to freedom of
speech." And so I took the job and I
dared them to do something about it and
they backed off. Were you still on
parole? Well, there is no federal uh
parole. Okay. I I I had uh two years of
probation, but you know that is you you
check in once a month and uh and assure
your probation officer that you haven't
been arrested in the previous month.
Right. Right. Right. Right. Bureau of
Prisons doesn't get to decide where I
work and where I can't work. Yeah,
that's right. Now, now the Bureau of
Prisons made that comment, but what
about the probation department? Did they
have a comment on this? She she had
approved it. Oh, boy. She had approved
it and then the BOP came back and said,
"No, no, no, no, no. Kiryaku is not
allowed to criticize
us." I said, "Yeah, that's what you
think." It's kind of like what they did
to Michael Cohen. They did the same
thing to him, too. Very much. Very much
so. Yes. Oh, boy. Um, I so I was going
to ask you I have here in my notes. Was
there have you had any retaliation from
the CIA since your big whistleblowering
episode? I has there been more
retaliation or is this about it? You
know what? If you had asked me a week
ago, I'd say no. Nothing. Nothing. But
just in the past week, um, I sent in,
you know, I every time I write something
that has to do with intelligence, I have
to send it to the CIA's publications
review board for review. They they're
supposed to make sure that it doesn't
reveal any classified information. So my
publisher I I've I've published seven
books now and contributed to an eighth.
My publisher had asked me to write a
series of four books. The CIA Insiders
Guide to the Iran Crisis, the CIA
Insiders Guide to Surveillance and
Surveillance Detection, The CIA Insiders
Guide to Lying and Lie Detection, and
The CIA Insiders Guide to Disappearing
and Living Off the Grid. So, the Iran
book came out like two years ago. The
the next three books are supposed to
come out uh May 25th, and the CIA
cleared all three of them. And then last
week I get an email saying, "Oh, hey, by
the way, that book that you wrote, this
the uh insiders guide to surveillance
and surveillance detection, we cleared
it, but there's another governmental
entity that uh wants to review it
because they may have an objection."
So, I wrote back and I said, "Well, I
never signed any secrecy agreements with
any other federal government entity. If
you guys cleared it, then it's cleared
and it's going to be published." And so,
they called me, which they're not
supposed to do because everything is
supposed to be in writing so we can
prove our side in court, right, if we
have to go to court. But they called me
and I said, "Look, at least be honest
and tell me, was this the FBI harassing
me?" And the guy said, "No, it was NSA."
I said, "Why in the world would
NSA care about a
book that talks about conducting
surveillance or surveillance
detection, you know, where you're just
driving around in a car following
somebody or driving around making sure
that nobody is following you." and he
said, "I don't know, but they said they
need it until April
22nd." So, I don't know if that's
harassment or not. I I will add one
other
thing. When I was um in prison, I was I
became very friendly with the Italian
contingent. And when I say Italian, I
mean Italians named Gambino,
Lucasy, you know, you get the idea.
Sure. So,
um, somebody came to my door one night
and, uh, rang the doorbell. It was about
7:30, and my youngest son, who was four
at the time, ran to the door and opened
it, and I could hear this sugary sweet
voice say, "Hi, is your daddy home?" And
I thought, "Oh, you sob." So, I went to
the door and I was kind of rude. I said,
"Um, may I help you?" And this guy in a
suit shows me his badge and breathless
breathlessly says, "Hi, Mr. Kuryaku. I'm
Agent Smith with the uh FBI, and this is
my colleague, Agent Jones." And I said,
"You guys have some nerve coming here.
You know, I'm represented by counsel. I
don't talk to you guys." Oh, he says,
"No, no, Mr. Kuryaku, it's not about
your case. Uh, it's about something
else. We were hoping we could get your
help. Well, again, very gutsy to come
and ask me for help. So, the guy says,
"We know that when you were at Lorettto,
you were friends with um Peter the
rabbit
Calibris." I said,
"So, well, Mr. Kuryaku, uh we have
reason to believe that uh that Pete is
home now. He got out." I said, "Yeah, so
good for good for Pete." Well, Mr.
Kuryaku, we have reason to believe that
Pete may have taken over leadership of
the Banano crime family. And I said,
"Oh, and you want me to rat out a five
family's
boss? Get off my
property." And I closed the door and I
called my
lawyer. And then he called me back and
he said, "Um, they said that they'll
never come to your house again."
And that's how we left it.
Well, never a dull moment for John
Keryaku. I'll tell you that, man. Now,
but John, you mentioned that you you
wrote all these books. I I actually went
looking on Amazon for your books, right
before the show because I said, you
know, let me promote the books for him.
I couldn't find any. Yeah, they're on
Amazon. Name correctly? I I copied from
Wikipedia.
Huh. Let me look. While we're talking,
I'm going to take a quick look. Well, we
got to take a commercial break anyway,
so this is a good time for John to to
check on Amazon and see if they're
screwing with him, too, in the past 24
hours. God forbid. I hope that that's
not happening. I'd hate to be the bearer
of bad news. But we're talking to John
Kiryaku. You could find him at his
website, which is john
Kuryaku.com. Uh, and also too, we're
going to be talking about uh this
article he just wrote about Rick Praau
in CovertAction Magazine. I actually I
was so uh enjoyed the article so much I
was so inspired I went and I purchased
all the back issues of uh covert action
which you could do be coming in the mail
shortly. Uh, we'll be right. Right.
Awesome. Right. I'm looking forward to
it. So, we'll be right back with more of
John Kyaku after these messages.
And now, a word from our sponsors. If
you find yourself in need of legal
representation, it can be a very
stressful time in your life. In my
career, I have dealt with thousands of
lawyers. I've dealt with thousands of
law firms. And I can confidently
recommend to you Keith M. Davidson at
kmdaw.com. Available 24 hours, 7 days a
week. Just log into
kmdlaw.com. That's
kmdaw.com. Or you can call toll-free
8334kmdaw. That's
8334kmdaw. Personal injury, wrongful
death, STDs, sexual assault, car
accidents. They handle it all
efficiently and professionally. It
doesn't matter how imposing the
opposition may be because the team at
kmdlaw.com are battle tested and fierce.
They will not stop until just prevails.
Go to kmdlaw.com or call toll-free
8334KMD Law. If you're in for the fight
of your life, stop screwing around and
contact KMD Law. Thank you so much for
listening to the Operan Report. I want
to welcome all our new listeners at WWPR
1490 a.m. in the Tampa Bay area. We're
brand new down here. We're getting a
nice warm welcome. We have great
advertising opportunities for local
sponsors, local businesses, but also
international websites and international
companies too on our other stations in
California, Nevada, Utah, and on the
internet worldwide. But down here in
Tampa Bay, Florida, we have some great
opportunities for you to come in and get
very, very affordable advertising rates.
Get a hold of me at
operanreportgmail.com and we'll cut you
a good deal. A flooded home or business
is never easy to deal with. You're left
with a mess to clean up, having to deal
with the insurance company to pay for
the damages, not to mention the memories
that are lost that you cannot replace.
An aquedam can be another tool in your
arsenal to protect your home or business
from the floodwaters, a hurricane, storm
surge, or the king tides. Give Aquedam a
call at
7077642119, or look us up online at
aquadam.net.
We can help. We're also offering 10% off
the price to anyone who mentions they
heard this ad on the Operan Report.
Email revealer.com. People ask me all
the time, "Hey, Ed, are you still a
private investigator?" I sure am. Go to
emailrevealer.com. We handle adoption
investigations, infidelity
investigations, where you give us your
spouse's email address. We trace it back
to online dating websites. Catch them
cheating online. Email tracing. Locate
or identify somebody from as little as
an anonymous email address. summon owe
your money, back child support. We can
find that deadbeat, locate his hidden
assets, locate his hidden bank accounts,
find his current place of employment,
and even assist you in obtaining a
judgment and recover that judgment for
you.
Emailrevealer.com. Digital forensics,
computer forensics, cell phone
forensics, recover deleted text
messages. Create a report that you can
use in court.
Emailrevealer.com 800572-9762.
It's the Operan Report. And now, here is
investigator Ed Opperman. Okay, welcome
back to the Opperman Report. I'm your
host, private investigator Ed Opperman.
You can find me on Twitter and Instagram
at Opperman Report. Uh we're talking
today former CIA agent, uh a convicted
whistleblower, uh John Kurikawa, John
Kuryaku. John Kuryaku. Uh and we did
find his Amazon. He's got all these
books up there. A bunch of dozen books
he's written. Uh Doing Time Like a Spy,
How the CIA Taught Me to Survive and
Thrive in Prison. How to disappear and
live off the grid. A CIA insiders guide.
There's great stuff, man. Lying and lie
detection. A CIA insiders guide. I would
love to pick that up. Uh surveillance
and surveillance detection is all great
stuff. Convenient terrorist to
whistleblowers stories of torture,
terror, secret wars, and CIA lies. Uh so
go to his website, John Kiryaku,
and.com, and find that there. But we're
talking today, too. I invited him to
come on the show to talk about this
piece he just wrote in Covert Action
Magazine. I invite him on about this,
then I bring up everything else in the
world. CIA CIA shadow warrior covers up
past as mob hitman as mob hitman in new
memoir being celebrated across
mainstream media. John, let it rip.
Well, Rick Praau was a 30 plus year uh
veteran of the CIA. He uh I I worked
briefly for him when I was at the CIA in
the counterterrorism center. He was the
chief of operations there. And before
that he did some work in something
called the special activities division.
You can draw your own conclusions as to
what they do for a living. Uh but uh
Rick Praau retired oh a while ago now
about 10 years ago and uh retired to
Florida and uh and wrote a book and the
book is a very typical normal uh CIA
memoir. He uh immigrated with his
parents uh from Cuba uh immediately
after the Cuban revolution. They fled
communism. And through the the course of
this book, he he tells you how much how
viscerally he hates communism, you know,
like I wanted to double tap those guys.
We hung Marxists from the from the light
posts and even the dogs hated Marxists.
You know, stuff like that. It was just
silly. And then there are like 120 pages
of Afghanistan and what he did in
Afghanistan. It's all fine and good, but
the point of the of the book review was
I I said there was something that he
left out that that I think the the
reader has a right to know. Uh there
have been credible reports in um Florida
newspapers and in Vanity Fair magazine
that before joining the CIA, Rick Praau
was a hitman for the Medí cartel. And
um these articles said that he was being
investigated by Miami Dade police for
seven contract killings, including the
stepson of Meer Lansky, who helped to
found the modern American mafia with
Lucky Luciano.
And um Rick had uh covered his tracks so
well that the Miami Dade police were
never able to build a a case against him
and he was able to pass the polygraph
into the CIA and um and uh made a very
long and successful CIA career. So I go
on to say, look, I don't know if he was
a hitman. I don't know if he was a drug
trafficker. I don't know if he came to
the CIA from the Medí cartel, but I do
know that a CIA psychiatrist once told
me that the CIA actively seeks to hire
people who have sociopathic tendencies,
not
sociopaths. Sociopaths have no
conscience. They're impossible to
control and they blow right through the
polygraph exam. People who have
sociopathic tendencies do have a
conscience but are comfortable working
in moral and legal gray areas. The
problem is when you're looking for
people who have sociopathic tendencies,
the actual sociopaths frequently slip
through the cracks.
So, I said, I don't know what he's done,
but I think that if he's going to come
out with a a memoir that is celebrated
in the Washington Post and the New York
Times and CNN and Fox News, he at least
owes the reader an explanation of what
in the world he was doing for a living
through the 1980s.
Okay. Now, now this is fascinating
stuff. Okay. So, my first question is,
you say he's living in Florida. Do you
know where in Florida? Uh yeah, in uh
St. Augustine. Okay, good. A little
distance there because I haven't moved
down to Florida myself. I got to wash my
step down here, man. I just I just got
here. I I don't I'm not
quite set up yet. Okay. I got to wash my
step. Now, you now you said too that you
worked for this fellow for a short
period of time. Hello, goodbye, good
morning, that kind of stuff. Yes. Did
were you aware of his reputation at that
time?
No. In fact, I even asked a colleague
before before Rick was promoted to uh to
chief of operations uh in the
counterterrorism center. Uh we sat like
20 feet away from each other and every
morning he'd come in and he'd say, "Hey,
John." I'd say, "Hey, Rick, you know,
how was your weekend?" "Good. How was
yours?" "It was good." And then he'd go
sit in his cube and I was sitting in my
cube. And finally, I asked a colleague
of mine, "What exactly does he do here?"
And my friend looked at me and he says,
"John, he works for the special
activities division. What do you think
he does here?" And I was like, "Oh,
okay." I knew not to ask any more
questions. Gotcha. Now, my understanding
of CIA recruitment is they go to
colleges, you know, like like American
University, like you mentioned before,
that's a hot spot, right? But but now,
but to to get these other type of guys,
where do they go searching them out?
Well, post 911, um well, first of all,
you're you're right. A a lot of
recruitments are made at colleges. I
would go so far as to say probably a
plurality of the recruitments that the
CIA makes are at colleges, right? I I
was recruited in in graduate school, for
example. Um, but post 911, a lot of
those recruitments are from guys who are
looking to get out of special forces.
The CIA has a lot of Navy Seals, Army
Rangers, you know, green berets, tough
guys, guys who can parachute in, pop off
a couple of shots, grab a target, and
then get out. Uh,
but even
earlier, you know, there were there were
a lot of people, how how should I say
this?
In certain parts of the world, there are
indigenous ongoing low-level wars,
right? Oftentimes, those wars uh center
around the international drug
trade. And CIA and DIA are competing
agencies. The CIA's job is not to deal
with international drugs. It's not to
stop drug traffickers, for example.
That's DEA's job. CIA's job is to
recruit spies to steal secrets. Period.
And so often times if you want to
infiltrate a group like the Medí cartel
or the Cali cartel
um or any of the Mexican cartels for
that matter, you need to get close to
them and you know then you make your
recruitment. Well, it's possible. It's
conceivable
that that's how it worked out in his
case. Again, I don't know. I'm
speculating. I'm not saying that Rick
Praau was a a drug trafficker. I'm not
saying that he was a hitman. I'm saying
there are reports out there saying he
was a drug trafficker and a hitman.
Gotcha. So then, and more generalities
because neither one of us want any
problems, right? A couple old fat We're
a couple old fat guys. Okay, we don't
want any any be problem. Leave this one
on top of Tell me about it. I know, man.
But now I I had um uh Rick Ricardo
Morales, the son on my show. His father
was Monkey Morales, right? Uh CIA sniper
training guy, right? And um uh it it
just seems because the same allegations
are around him, you know? Sure. Right.
Coke smuggling, all this stuff. It seems
that uh how does that work? like they're
just no one questions them about it or
they know they're doing it or
um yes and yes. You know the the thing
is too that
really let's say let's say that you are
a drug trafficker, right? But you have
access to the to the head of a cartel.
Well, we want to know what the head of
the cartel is thinking, saying,
planning, you know, where where is he
going to expand? What's his network look
like? Where does he launder his money?
All all of those issues we'd be
interested in knowing. So, I meet you.
It turns out you work for this guy. So,
I'm gonna start sch smoozing with you.
I'm going to take you to dinner. I'm
gonna introduce my wife to your wife.
Maybe we're going to go on vacation
together. I'm going to spend some money
on you. Maybe a lot of money on you. And
then I'm going to pitch you and I'm
going to ask you to report back to me
on, you know, what your boss is doing
there. I've recruited you.
Um, are you a nice guy? That doesn't
really matter. You're probably a bad
guy, but you're working for the good
guys now. And so the CIA would be
willing to overlook a lot of the
problems that you bring to the
relationship so long as you're
productive, you know, so long as you
give us actionable intelligence, so long
as you expand our body of understanding
of that
cartel. You know, I I recruited a guy
once that had that had committed a a
murder. It was a coldblooded murder. And
when it got time to the point of
recruitment, he said to me, "Look, you
know, I I killed this guy a couple of
years ago." Well, I knew he had killed
the guy. And I said, "I I'm not your
confessor, right? You and I have a
business relationship. I don't care what
you've done in the past. It's none of my
business. So long as you give me the
information that I need and I pay you
the salary that you earn, that's our
relationship. I don't care what you've
done before we
met." And that's really the CIA view.
So, okay, so they someone who has a a
background in this area of drug
smuggling goes to becomes an informant
for central intelligence, right? And and
they kind of say, "Okay, well, here's my
business card. If you get pulled over,
uh, don't worry about it. Just they have
them call me up and we're going to get
you out of this." No. No. Go ahead. uh
you know, if if you get arrested for
something like big and you're looking
for or you're looking at like
significant prison
time, there are two
ways that this can play out. Number one,
the station chief might go to the head
of your country's intelligence service
and say, "Look, I'm going to ask for a
favor. this guy you arrested over here,
he's actually my guy. So, can you please
let him go? 99 times out of a 100red,
they're going to let you
go. But there are some times where the
CIA says, "Well, tough luck. You're on
your own." And then we see people as
they go to trial invoke something called
the CIA defense, right? Where they say,
"Hey, wait a minute. This isn't a crime.
I was doing this on behalf of the CIA."
which may or may not be true, but in
cases like that, the CIA just walks
away. They have no comment and you're on
your own. Yeah. And you hear about that
a lot, those cases with the stinger
missiles and stuff, you know, right?
Absolutely. Yeah. Um, do you regret ever
getting involved with these characters?
Yes. Yeah, actually. You know, it's
funny. Nobody ever asks me that. People
always ask me if I regret blowing the
whistle.
But nobody's ever asked me if I regret
getting involved. Yeah. And uh so yeah,
this is my opportunity to say, "Dang it,
I should have gone to film school."
Yeah. And and would you suggest, you
know, recommend to kids, you know, at
American University that hey, when they
come around with that recruitment booth,
just keep walking.
You know, I that that's a little bit
harder to um to answer because I
consider myself to be anti-CIA, of
course, but at the same time, I'm a
realist and I know that there will
always be a CIA. And the only way to
change it, unless you're going to get
yourself elected to Congress and sit on
the on the uh intelligence committee,
the oversight committee, the only way to
really change the CIA is from the
inside. you know, around 10 years of
your career, or I should say year 10 of
your career at the
CIA, that's when people, some people's
careers begin to take off and they begin
to move into leadership positions. Well,
if you've been at the CIA for 15 years
and you're doing pretty well, you're
going to find yourself in a position
where you can actually affect policy,
you can change policy, and you might be
able to make the place, you know, better
or more
law-abiding. So, I I understand that the
CIA is not going away. Congress isn't
going to do away with it. It's not going
to just cease to exist. If we're going
to change it, it has to be changed from
the inside.
John, we're just about out of time.
Uh, is there something I haven't
answered about all this stuff that you'd
like the audience to know about? Yeah,
these are these are great questions. I'm
glad you brought them up. Thank you. And
thanks for allowing me the opportunity
to, you know, clarify some of these uh
these stories that have been out there.
Yeah, it's amazing, right? That what the
media does no homework. You know, they
did but by the way, before they publish
all that stuff about you quoting you
saying this stuff, did anybody contact
you to get a clarification? not a soul.
And you know what's crazy? The original
article
um had attached to it a video of me
giving the speech. It's like the guy who
wrote the article didn't even bother to
watch his own video that he attached to
the article. But wasn't the first
article like in Before It's News,
something like that. Yeah. It was
something ridiculous. Crazy. Yeah,
exactly. Okay, John. Uh Kiryaku, thank
you so much. Uh we got to have you come
back and talk about some of these books,
man. surveillance and the detection. I
would love to have you come back and
good luck with with the radio show and
digging out from under this censorship.
Now, if people want to support your
work, how can they support John Kuryaku?
Oh, thank you. Uh, you know what? You
can go to
johnkuryaku.com. Um, check it out there.
Uh, some of the books are are on the
site, the ones that are out of print or
are for sale on the site. And um yeah,
uh Amazon.com and listen to the show and
drop me an email. And the show is on a
Rumble now. You can hear it on Rumble.
It's on Rumble. Yes. It's called
Political Misfits. Like the Jets and the
Sharks. Just think of that. Now it's
John Kuryaku. K I R I A
Ko.com. Uh John, thank you so much, man.
Thanks for having me. Good night.
[Music]
And now a word from our sponsors. Hey,
if you have something you want to
promote, like a business or a website,
you got a big event coming up, uh
consider advertising on the Operan
Report, uh we have excellent advertising
rates for you. We're on
KCAA on uh three different frequencies
on AMFM in California, KSHP of 1400 AM
in uh uh Nevada, uh WWPR in Florida, the
Tampa Bay area, 1490 AM, and also
WWN, which is on the east coast of
Florida, all the way from Miami up to
Port Bay, uh
with 175 miles of I95. Uh the
advertising rates are very affordable.
Uh once your ad goes up and we play the
show on the podcast and on the YouTube
channel, uh those ads stay up there
forever and then we play repeats every
single night of classic oper shows and
your new ads will be inserted into those
repeats that play every single night. So
the the saturation is incredible and the
rates are very
affordable. Contact me at
operanreport@gmail.com.
A flooded home or business is never easy
to deal with. You're left with a mess to
clean up, having to deal with the
insurance company to pay for the
damages, not to mention the memories
that are lost that you cannot replace.
An aquedam can be another tool in your
arsenal to protect your home or business
from the floodwaters, a hurricane, storm
surge, or the king tides. Give AquadamAM
a call at
707764-2119 or look us up online at
aquedam.net. We can help. We're also
offering 10% off the price to anyone who
mentions they heard this ad on the
Operan Report. If you find yourself in
need of legal representation, it can be
a very stressful time in your life. In
my career, I have dealt with thousands
of lawyers. I've dealt with thousands of
law firms. And I can confidently
recommend to you Keith M. Davidson at
kmdaw.com. Available 24 hours, 7 days a
week. Just log into
kmdlaw.com. That's
kmdaw.com. Or you can call tollfree
8334kmdaw. That's
8334kmdaw. Personal injury, wrongful
death, STDs, sexual assault, car
accidents. They handle it all
efficiently and professionally. It
doesn't matter how imposing the
opposition may be because the team at
kmdlaw.com are battle tested and fierce.
They will not stop until just prevails.
Go to kmdlaw.com or call toll-free 8334
KMD Law. If you're in for the fight of
your life, stop screwing around and
contact KMD Law. Before Epstein was the
Franklin coverup, before that the
Finders and long before that, the
Cleveland Street scandal. Pedogate
Primer is a concise intro and overview
of a growing child abuse epidemic
worldwide. It features shocking
instances of institutionalized and
organizational pedophilia throughout
history. Churches, cults, the world of
arts and entertainment, the government,
NOS, charities, and major corporations
are all complicit or culprits in many
instances. Pedogate Primer delves into
material that for many may seem like the
stuff of conspiracy theories. For this
reason, the book draws on academic
resources, declassified documents, and
other reliable sources and steers clear
of conjecture. Such shocking true
stories need no embellishment.
emailrevealer.com. People ask me all the
time, "Hey, Ed, are you still a private
investigator?" I sure am. Go to
emailrevealer.com. We handle adoption
investigations, infidelity
investigations where you give us your
spouse's email address. We trace it back
to online dating websites, catch him
cheating online, email tracing, locate
or identify somebody from as little as
an anonymous email address, summon owe
your money, back child support. We can
find that deadbeat, locate his hidden
assets, locate his hidden bank accounts,
find his current place of employment,
and even assist you in obtaining a
judgment and recover that judgment for
you.
emailrevealer.com. Digital forensics,
computer forensics, cell phone
forensics, recover deleted text
messages. Create a report that you can
use in court.
emailrevealer.com
8005729762. Hey guys, if you like the
show and you want to show your support,
uh check out the Operman Report Patreon.
Uh you can go there and become a member
uh for $3 a month. We have all the shows
that you hear Monday through Friday on
AMFM radio. We have all those shows, but